A Finding Aid to the Constance Glenn Papers, 1960s-2014, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Exhibition Files, 1979-2003; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 2.1 Linear feet Box 7-10; 3.53 Gigabytes ER06-ER07
  - A Happening Place (2003), Correspondence and Papers, 2001-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 7-8)
  - A Happening Place (2003), Research Material, circa 2001-2003; Archival Resource Key; Conrtains born-digital materials, see ER06 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - A Happening Place (2003), Research Material, Digital Photographs, 2002; Archival Resource Key; 0.129 Gigabytes 45 computer files (Folder ER06)
  - A Happening Place (2003), Writings, circa 2001-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - A Happening Place (2003), "Behind Pop Art: America in the 60s", Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - A Happening Place (2003), Symposium, 2003 April 29; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital materials, see ER07 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - A Happening Place (2003), Symposium, Digital Video Recording, April 29, 2003; Archival Resource Key; 3.4 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER07)
  - Candida Hofer: Architecture of Absence (2004), Correspondence, circa 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
  - Candida Hofer: Architecture of Absence (2004), Writings, circa 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 15-16)
  - Candida Hofer: Architecture of Absence (2004), Printed Material, 1998-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Professional Files, 1979-2007; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 1.3 Linear feet Box 11-12
  Professional Files document Constance Glenn's involvement with associations, other museums, and galleries, as well as her participation in lectures, panel discussions, and juried competitions. Included is correspondence, transcripts, some writings and research material, audiovisual material, and printed matter.
  - American Association of Museums, Papers, 1985-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Archives of American Art, Papers, 1985-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Archives of American Art, Whittington Photography, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Archives of American Art, "Passage to Maturity: The Los Angeles Art World, 1930-1950," Symposium, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Archives of American Art, Inventories and Lists, 1989-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Archives of American Art, Directory of Repositories for Visual Arts in Southern California, 1900-1950, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Archives of American Art, David Hockney Award Event, 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
  - Archives of American Art, Trips and Tours, 1992, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - ArtExpress, San Francisco and Pittsburgh ToursTours, circa 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
  - Art/LA, Papers, 1987-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - ArtTable, Inc., Papers, 1989-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, Papers, 1985-1989, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 14-15)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, Conference Packages, 1997-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 16-18)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, Burnout Seminar, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - California Arts Council, Papers, 1985-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Center for the Study of Decorative Arts, Loan, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - College Art Association, "Edward Weston and Frank Zeitlin," Research Material, 1910-1980s, circa 1979-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - College Art Association, Drafts and Papers, 1984-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Curator's Circle, Tours, 1997, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Friends of Photography, Papers, 1985-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - International Committee for Modern Art Museums, Speech, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - J. Paul Getty Trust Fund for the Visual Arts, Papers, 1987-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - University of Minnesota, James Rosenquist Speech, 2001-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - The Music Center, Correspondence, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, Papers and Correspondence, 1988-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Oracle Conference, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Public Corporation for the Arts, Papers, circa 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Pasadena Arts Alliance, Video, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Royal Academy of Art, David Hockney Lecture, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Associations and Societies, Miscellaneous, 1985-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Presentations and Consulting, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Juror and Review Boards, 1988-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 5)
- California State University, Long Beach, Files, 1975-2001; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 1.8 Linear feet Box 12-13; 0.051 Gigabytes ER08
  California State University, Long Beach files document Constance Glenn's tenure as an educator and museum director at CSULB. Glenn helped found the university's museum, the University Art Museum, in 1973 as she was completing her M.A. in Fine Art. She initiated CSULB's Graduate Certificate in Museum Studies, and taught courses on art and museum studies. The papers mostly include administrative records such as correspondence, performance review files, and resumes. Also included are research files and manuscript drafts that were compiled for an M.A. thesis regarding art collector Marcia Weisman. Glenn served as a supervisor for this project.
  - Resumes, circa 1978-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 6-8)
  - Dossier, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 9-10)
  - Performance Review, 1996-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Administrative Files, Awards, Promotions, 1978-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Papers, 1984-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
  - Manual for the Preparation of an Exhibition as Exemplified by Constance Glenn (1975), Digital Photographs, 2014; Archival Resource Key; 0.051 Gigabytes 23 computer files (Folder ER08)
  - University Art Museum, Spain and France Trip, 1986-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 16-17)
  - University Art Museum, Span Trip, 1986-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 18-19)
  - University Art Museum, Contemporary Arts Council, Trips and Tours, circa 1986-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 20-21)
  - "If Memory Serves," by Constance Glenn, circa 1995; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - University Art Museum, Commercial, 2001 July; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Printed Material, 1980-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2-3)
  - Alison Hahn M.A. Thesis on Marcia Weisman, Manuscript, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Alison Hahn M.A. Thesis on Marcia Weisman, Papers, 1994-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Alison Hahn M.A. Thesis on Marcia Weisman, Meetings, circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Alison Hahn M.A. Thesis on Marcia Weisman, Interview Request Letters, 1994-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Alison Hahn M.A. Thesis on Marcia Weisman, Interview Transcripts, circa 1994-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Alison Hahn M.A. Thesis on Marcia Weisman, Notes, circa 1994-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Alison Hahn M.A. Thesis on Marcia Weisman, Writings and Notes, circa 1994-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 10-11)
  - Alison Hahn M.A. Thesis on Marcia Weisman, Bibliography Draft, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Alison Hahn M.A. Thesis on Marcia Weisman, Research Subject Files, circa 1994-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 13-19)
- Art Inventory and Sale Records, circa 1960s-1980s; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Box 13-14
  Art Inventory and Sale Records consists of notes, research, printed material, and gallery records regarding the sale, transfer, and provenance of artwork.
  - Research, Painting Inventories and Purchases, 1936-1986, circa 1986-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Inventory Cards, 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
  - Research, Painting Inventories and Purchases, 1936-1986, circa 1986-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Inventories of Collections and Exhibits, 1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Sandy and Harold Price Inventory, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Note on Sale of Mondrian and Kline Art, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Printed Material, 1960s-2014; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 1.5 Linear feet Box 14-15
  Printed Material consists of articles and clippings written by, regarding, or of general interest to Constance Glenn; periodicals; exhibition and event announcements from artists including Andy Warhol, Roy Lichtenstein, and Jim Dine; ephemera from the Jack Glenn Gallery; and some topical research files.
  - Jack Glenn Gallery, 1967-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Event and Exhibition Announcements, Jim Dine, 1979-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Event and Exhibition Announcements, David Hockney, 2006-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Event and Exhibition Announcements, Roy Lichtenstein, 1998-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Event and Exhibition Announcements, James Rosenquist, 2002-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Event and Exhibition Announcements, Lucas Samaras, 1993-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Event and Exhibition Announcements, Wayne Thiebaud, circa 1993-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Event and Exhibition Announcements, Andy Warhol, 2002-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 15-16)
  - Event and Exhibition Announcements, Tom Wesselmann, 1999-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Event and Exhibition Announcements, Groups and Solo Shows, circa 1980s-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Event and Exhibition Announcements, Groups and Solo Shows, circa 1980s-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Exhibition Posters, 1966-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Collection Catalogs and Auction Lists, circa 1985-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Robert Rauschberg Memorial, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Constance Glenn Writings, 1980s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Print Collector's Newsletter, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Material about Constance Glenn, 1985-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Article on the Glenn Family, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Architectural Digest, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
  - Periodicals, 1986-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 12-15)
  - Articles on Warhol's Silver Clouds and Print Portfolios, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, Frank Gehry, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Clippings and Articles, 1960s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 18-22)
  - "Fine Arts Forever" Bumper Sticker, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 23)
- Photographs, circa 1960s-2000s; Series 11; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Box 16-17
  Photographs include images of artwork, gallery and museum installations, and scenes from museum events. The bulk of the files are composed of photographs of Jim Dine's artwork. Also included are photographs of Glenn's personal library and some portraits.
  - Constance Glenn, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Glenn Library, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Steve Martin, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - "Tom, Aug. 15", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Jim Dine, Reproductions, 1970s-2000s, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 5-12)
  - Jim Dine, Reproductions, 1970s-2000s, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
  - Slides, Artwork and Gallery Installations, circa 1970s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 4-7)
  - Slides, Artwork, Artists, and Miscellaneous Images, circa 1970s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 8-10)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Sculptures, Paintings, and Photographs, 1960s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 11)